{
    "id": "26310db7c83f486ca591a8e9269929fe",
    "title": "Degrees Of Comparison Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "She is senior ................................... me by five years.",
            "description": "The adjectives senior and junior are followed by the preposition to.",
            "answers": [
                "than",
                "of",
                "to"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "94fea8143b4444389bce5c04c43eca47"
        },
        {
            "question": "My job is superior ..................................... yours.",
            "description": "The adjectives superior and inferior are followed by the preposition to.",
            "answers": [
                "than",
                "of",
                "to"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "d52773baf93d41a5bd05bd21bab95353"
        },
        {
            "question": "James is ........................................  his brother.",
            "description": "We use the comparative to compare one person or thing with another person or thing.",
            "answers": [
                "tallest of",
                "taller than",
                "taller then"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a2e0b007f45a4896a1018f168a805ec4"
        },
        {
            "question": "She sings ......................................... as her sister.",
            "description": "We use constructions with as...as... to say that two persons or things are similar.",
            "answers": [
                "as best",
                "as well",
                "better"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ceb9fdcc5f6b4d2c91036b591648ec5d"
        },
        {
            "question": "I earn as ..................................... money as you do.",
            "description": "Adjectives or adverbs of the positive degree are used in this construction.",
            "answers": [
                "much",
                "more",
                "much more"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "38996d9333e04ca0bfbccaab7bc45b5c"
        },
        {
            "question": "Samuel is ........................................ of the four boys.",
            "description": "We use the superlative to compare one or thing with the group to which that person or thing also belongs.",
            "answers": [
                "taller than",
                "tallest than",
                "the tallest"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "49fadb9352e547c396ced45885cee192"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am quite …………………………….. with what I have achieved.",
            "description": "We use the positive adjective when there is no idea of comparison.",
            "answers": [
                "happy",
                "happier",
                "happiest"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "32271b4d752d41099908873778c7d90f"
        },
        {
            "question": "This is …………………………… difficult problem I have ever encountered.",
            "description": "We make the superlative form of difficult with most. The article the is used before superlative adjectives.",
            "answers": [
                "the more",
                "the most",
                "most"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "afb4738f2dd346d3b910ed4342626289"
        },
        {
            "question": "You are …………………………… woman I have ever met.",
            "description": "The superlative form of kind is kindest.",
            "answers": [
                "the kindest",
                "the most kind",
                "the most kindest"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "d68aea3ef16e4c7d9649a26bb5196cac"
        },
        {
            "question": "This is as interesting …………………………. that.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "than",
                "as",
                "so"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f8b5557769e6467ba5112fb444f657f0"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am …………………………….. in movies than concerts.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "most interested",
                "more interested",
                "as interested"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b04b33e45a6046c9a700397d1a1834f4"
        },
        {
            "question": "You are no ............................................. him.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "better of",
                "better than",
                "best of"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "7ef21cff9c3547f680c156cb74f6cac9"
        }
    ]
}